A Finding Aid to the Colette Roberts Papers and Interviews with Artists, 1918-1971, in the Archives of American Art AAA.robecoli
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1938-1971; Series 5; (Box 3-5, 11-12; 2.0 linear feet)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1938-1971 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Checklists and Acquisition Lists, circa 1958-1970; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1950-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters from the Aurelia, 1958-1968; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Newsletters from L'Association des Membres de L'Ordre des Palmes Academiques, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Pamphlets, Art-Related, circa 1952-1970; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - Pamphlets, Other, circa 1948-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
  - Periodicals (Box 4)
    - Miscellaenous Periodicals, 1945, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - 57th Street Review, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Art Digest Newsletter, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Iris Time Unlimited, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Postcards, circa 1920-1960 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Posters, circa 1960-1970; (OV item housed in OV 12) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, circa 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases for Exhibitions, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Programs for Cultural Events, circa 1957-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Publications, circa 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcements (Oversized material from Box 4, folders 3-4) (Box 11 (OV))
  - Oversized Posters (Oversized materials from Box 4, folder 33) (Box 12 (OV))
- Photographs, circa 1930-1971; Series 6; (Box 5; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains photographs of Colette Roberts, artists and other unidentified people, art spaces, and works of art. Most of the photographs of people are unidentified, but those that are identified have been filed by name. The photograph of Ad Reinhardt with Roberts' class was taken for her "Meet the Artist" course at New York University, during which she produced many of the interviews in Series 8: Interviews with Artists. The Tamarind Lithography Workshop photographs show fellows at the workshop in the studio in 1962, including Richard Diebenkorn, John Hultberg, Joyce Trieman, Adja Yunkers, among others. Exhibition photographs include a 1965 show at Grand Central Moderns of work by Jennett Lam.
  - Colette Roberts, circa 1956-1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Ad Reinhardt with Colette Roberts and Class, circa 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Thérèse Le Prat, circa 1930-1950 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Mike Nevelson, Betty Parsons, circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop Artists, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified people, 1960-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Exhibitions and Installations, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Museum Architecture, 1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Works of Art, 1954-1971; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
- Artwork circa 1940-1969, Series 7; (Box 5; 4 folders)
  This series contains Fluxus art stamps, a printed picture of Ray Johnson stamped "DOUGHNUT FESTIVAL," sketches of Aaron Copeland made by Jennett Lam, other unattributed sketches, and a pressed tin figure.
  - Fluxpost 17-cent Stamps, circa 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Ray Johnson Piece, circa 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sketches of Copeland by Jennett Lam, circa 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches and Pressed Tin Figure, circa 1940-1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Interviews with Artists, 1959-1971; Series 8; (Box 5-10; 5.5 linear feet)
  This series contains taped interviews with artists, a card index of the interview series, and a few notes and transcripts related to the interviews.
  Most of the recordings in this series are interviews with artists that Roberts created during a class she taught at New York University between 1957 and 1971 called "Meet the Artist." In this class, she brought her students to the studios of working artists to interview them about their work, and in the early 1960s, Roberts began recording these interviews on audio reels. Also found is a tape in which Roberts describes her intentions with the "Meet the Artist" program. Other recordings in this series include interviews with Chryssa, Adolph Gottlieb, and Louise Nevelson for a series Roberts called "The Presence of the Artist," for which interviews were transcribed and edited by their subjects. A few of the recordings of Marcel Duchamp were not created by Roberts, including three interviews and various lectures and performances by Duchamp. Miscellaneous recordings of Roberts' own classes and lectures are also found, mostly scattered on the second sides of some of the tapes with artist interviews. Some of the interviews are in French.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  Subseries 8.1: Card Index and Notes, 1964-1970
  Subseries 8.2: Transcripts, 1963-1970
  Subseries 8.3: Sound Recordings, 1959-1971
  - Card Index and Notes, 1964-1970; 8.1
    The card index provides useful confirmation of the date and sometimes location of Roberts' interviews with artists. However, it is not comprehensive; it contains references to interviews not held in the collection, and there are interviews in the present collection that are not represented in card index. Several interviews documented in the index appear to have been donated to Syracuse University. Notes include appointment slips, Roberts' lists of subjects, and a transcript of an interview of Roberts for an unspecified Radio program about her "Meet the Artist" series.
    Cards are arranged in loose alphabetical order.
    - Card Index (Box 5)
      - A-G, 1964-1970 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - H-N, 1964-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - O-Z, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Notes, circa 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Transcripts, 1963-1970; 8.2
    Transcripts for nine interviews are found. Dates on the transcripts refer to the date of the interview, and not the transcript. The actual transcripts are undated. Some of the transcripts are annotated and edited, presumably by their subject. Sound recordings to which the transcripts correspond are noted in Series 8.3.
    Transcripts are arranged alphabetically by interviewee.
    - Mary Bauermeister, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Kathleen Cooke, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Marcel Duchamp, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - John Hultberg, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Jennett Lam interviewed by Arlene Jacobowitz, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      (Transcript is incomplete)
    - Jennett Lam, 1968; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
    - Richard Lindner, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Sound Recordings, 1959-1971; 8.3
    This series contains 124 interviews with artists conducted by Colette Roberts, as well as scattered lectures, broadcast recordings, and other miscellaneous sound recordings created and collected by Roberts. Recordings are on 149 sound tape reels (1/4 in. tape). Interviews are listed by individual recording below.
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Roberts often made duplicate copies or excerpts of interviews she had conducted, and where duplicates and excerpts exist among her reels they are listed with what is thought to be the original or earliest generation recording in the collection. All of the sound recordings have been digitized for research access.
    Sound recordings are arranged in rough alphabetical order by interviewee. Where different subjects were taped on the same reel, they are listed together in order to reflect the physical arrangement of the interviews on the reels. Cross-references are provided for subjects occurring out of order.
    - Sam Adler, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 35, Item 1)
    - George Ortman, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 35, Item 2)
    - Sam Adler, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 35, Item 3)
    - Peter Agostini, (see Box 6, item 10) (Box 5)
    - Joseph Albers, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 36, Item 4)
    - Arman, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 36, Item 5)
    - Alice Baber, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 37, Item 6)
    - Paul Jenkins, 1965; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 37, Item 7)
    - Erwin S. Barrie, 1966; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 5, Folder 37, Item 8)
    - Mary Bauermeister, 1967; (1 side of 1 original sound tape reel, and 2 duplicate sound tape reels; transcript available in Box 5, folder 24) (Box 5, Folder 38-39, Item 9)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, 1967; (1 side of 1 original sound tape reel, and 5 sound tape reels containing duplicates and excerpts) (Box 5, Folder 38-41, Item 10)
      (original interview is on side B of reel with original Mary Bauermeister interview, in folder 38)
    - Romare Bearden, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 1)
    - Isabel Bishop, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 2)
    - Roger Bissière, circa 1961-1971; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 3)
    - Unidentified Artist, First Name François, circa 1961-1971; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 4)
    - Ilya Bolotowsky, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 5)
    - Henry Botkin, circa 1961-1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 6)
    - Stanley Boxer, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 7)
    - James Brooks, 1968; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 6, Item 8)
    - James Brooks, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 9)
    - Peter Agostini, circa 1968; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 10)
    - Kenneth Campbell, before 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 11)
    - Kenneth Campbell, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 12)
    - Tad Miyashita, (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 13)
    - Victor Candell, 1969 February 20; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 14)
    - Victor Candell, 1969 December; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 15)
    - Giorgio Cavallon, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 16)
    - Giorgio Cavallon, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 17)
    - Chryssa, 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 18)
    - Chryssa, "Presence of the Artist" Interview, 1970; (6 original sound tape reels, 3 duplicate sound tape reels) (Box 6, Item 19)
    - Kathleen Cooke, 1970; (1 sound tape reel; transcript available in box 5, folder 25) (Box 6, Item 20)
    - Ben Cunningham, 1968; (1 original and 1 duplicate sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 21)
    - Ben Cunningham, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 22)
    - Hubert Damisch, 1966; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 23)
    - Hubert Damisch Lecture about Honoré de Balzac, 1966; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 24)
    - John Day, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 6, Item 25)
    - George Deem, 1968; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 6, Item 26)
    - Dorothy Dehner, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 1)
    - Dorothy Dehner, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 2)
    - Colette Roberts Teaching a French Class, circa 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 3)
    - Dorothy Dehner, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 4)
    - François Dicko, (see Box 8, item 3) (Box 7)
    - Marcel Duchamp, Interviews by Colette Roberts (Box 7)
      - Marcel Duchamp, 1963; (2 sound tape reels; transcript available in Box 5, folder 26) (Box 7, Item 5)
      - Marcel Duchamp, 1964; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 7, Item 6)
        (In French)
      - Marcel Duchamp, 1964 or 1965; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 7)
      - Marcel Duchamp Interviewed at Knoedler Gallery, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 8)
      - Marcel Duchamp, 1968; (2 original and 1 duplicate sound tape reels) (Box 7, Item 9)
      - Marcel Duchamp, circa 1961-1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 10)
      - Marcel Duchamp, circa 1961-1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 11)
        (In English)
      - Colette Roberts Lecture on French Art History, circa 1961-1971; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 12)
      - Marcel Duchamp, circa 1968-1968; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 13)
        (Fragment, in English)
    - Excerpts of Marcel Duchamp Interviews by Colette Roberts (Box 7)
      - Excerpt from Duchamp Interview about Ready-mades, circa 1964; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 14)
      - Excerpt from Duchamp Interview about Pop Art, circa 1965; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 15)
      - Excerpts from Duchamp Interview, 1968; (6 sound tape reels) (Box 7, Item 16)
    - Leo Manso, 1968 October; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 17)
    - Marcel Duchamp, Interviews by Others (Box 7)
      - "Art, Anti-Art: Marcel Duchamp Speaks,", 1959; (4 sound tape reels) (Box 7, Item 18)
        (Interview for the BBC conducted by George Heard Hamilton and Richard Hamilton)
      - Interview by Two Unidentified Men, circa 1968; (2 original sound tape reels and 1 duplicate sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 19)
        (Tape is labeled "Eagle," and may be Arnold Eagle and Lewis Jacobs)
      - Unidentified Broadcast Interview, circa 1958-1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 20)
    - Marcel Duchamp, Lectures and Performances (Box 7)
      - Dictionary, circa 1959; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 21)
      - MoMA Lecture on Ready-Mades, 1961; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 22)
      - Marcel Duchamp at Ekstrom Gallery, circa 1965; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 23)
    - Frédérique Duran, (See Box 10, item 13) (Box 7)
    - Jimmy Ernst, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 7, Item 24)
    - John Ferren, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 1)
    - Mark Gabor, (see box 8, item 17) (Box 8)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, Interview Excerpts, 1964; (2 sound tape reels; transcript of entire interview available in box 5, folder 27) (Box 8, Item 2)
      (Complete original recording of interview not extant)
    - François Dicko, 1964; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel; found on reel 1 of 1964 Gottlieb Interview Excerpts) (Box 8, Item 3)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, 1965; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 4)
    - John Hultberg, 1966; (1 original sound tape reel, found on side B of 1965 Gottlieb interview; and 1 duplicate sound tape reel; transcript available in box 5, folder 28) (Box 8, Item 5)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, 1967, (see box 5, folder 38) (Box 8)
    - Adolph Gottlieb, "Presence of the Artist" Interview, 1970; (1 original and 3 duplicate sound tape reels) (Box 8, Item 6)
    - Jose Guerrero, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 7)
    - David Hare, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 8)
    - Leon Hartl, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 9)
    - Leon Hartl, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 10)
    - Colette Roberts Lecture on Louise Nevelson at MoMA, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 11)
    - William Stanley Hayter, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 12)
    - Carl Holty, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 13)
    - Budd Hopkins, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 14)
    - John Hultberg, 1966, (See box 8, item 5) (Box 8)
    - John Hultberg, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 15)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on Contemporary Art, Fragment, circa 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 16)
    - René Huyghe, 1965; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 17)
    - Paul Jenkins, 1965, (See box 5, folder 37) (Box 8)
    - Paul Jenkins and Mark Gabor, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 18)
      (Gabor interview is the last five minutes of side 2 of this reel)
    - Ray Johnson, circa 1961-1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 19)
    - Howard Kanovitz, 1967 or later; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 20)
    - Howard Kanovitz, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 21)
    - Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, Fragment of Unidentified Radio Program, circa 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 22)
      (Recorded off the air)
    - Ivan Karp with Bernar Venet, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 23)
    - Robert John Kaupelis, 1970; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 8, Item 25)
    - Jennett Lam, 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 8, Item 26)
    - Jennett Lam, 1966; (4 sound tape reels) (Box 8, Item 27)
      (This is a separate interview from item 26)
    - Jennett Lam, 1968; (3 sound tape reels; transcript available in box 5, folders 30-32) (Box 8, Item 28)
    - Jennett Lam, 1971; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 1)
    - Colette Roberts, Radio Interview by Eden Gray, circa 1959; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 2)
    - Jennett Lam, Interview by Arlene Jacobowitz of the Brooklyn Museum, 1966; (2 sound tape reels; partial transcript available in box 5, folder 29) (Box 9, Item 3)
    - Stanley Lansman, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 4)
    - Thérèse Le Prat, 1966; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 5)
    - Unidentified Male Artist, circa 1966; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 6)
    - John Levee, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 7)
    - Miriam Schapiro, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 8)
    - Roy Lichtenstein, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 9)
    - Richard Lindner, 1965; (2 original sound tape reels, 1 duplicate sound tape reel; transcript available in box 5, folder 33) (Box 9, Item 10)
    - David Lund, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 11)
    - Leo Manso, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 12)
    - Leo Manso, 1968, (See box 7, item 17) (Box 9)
    - Leo Manso, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 13)
      (This is a separate interview from item 12)
    - Marisol, circa 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 14)
    - Jeanne Patterson Miles, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 15)
    - Tad Miyashita, (See box 6, item 13) (Box 9)
    - Sibyl Moholy-Nagy, (See box 8, item 23) (Box 9)
    - Seong Moy, 1969; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 16)
    - Robert Natkin, 1968; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 9, Item 17)
    - Lowell Nesbitt, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 18)
    - Mark Nesbitt, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 19)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1964 May 5; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 20)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1968 May 13; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 21)
    - Louise Nevelson, Excerpt, 1968 Fall; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel; excerpt of item 23) (Box 9, Item 22)
    - Louise Nevelson, 1968 Fall; (1 sound tape reel; transcript available in box 5, folder 34) (Box 9, Item 23)
    - Louise Nevelson, "Presence of the Artist" Interview, 1970; (1 original sound tape reel, 1 duplicate sound tape reel, and 2 reels with excerpts) (Box 9, Item 24)
    - Louise Nevelson, Colette Roberts Lecture, Notes, and Excerpts from Interviews, 1969; (2 sound tape reels; see box 8, item 12 for complete lecture, and box 9, item 30 for another excerpt used in the lecture) (Box 9, Item 25)
    - Mike Nevelson, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 26)
    - Raphael Soyer, 1967; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 27)
    - Giora Novak, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 28)
    - Giora Novak, circa 1970; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 29)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on Louise Nevelson, Excerpt, 1969; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 30)
    - Brian O'Doherty, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 31)
    - Ortman, Samuel (See box 5, folder 35, item 2) (Box 9)
    - Betty Parsons, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 32)
    - Bernard Pfriem, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 9, Item 33)
    - Abraham Rattner, 1968; (3 original sound tape reels, 3 duplicate sound tape reels) (Box 10, Item 1)
    - Unidentified Musical Performance, circa 1968; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel; side B of reel 3 of Rattner 1968 interview) (Box 10, Item 2)
    - Man Ray, 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 3)
    - Robert Reid, 1970; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 10, Item 4)
    - Colette Roberts, Comments on the "Meet the Artist" Course at NYU, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 5)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on Contemporary Art, Fragment, (See box 8, item 17) (Box 10)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on French Art History, (See box 7, item 12) (Box 10)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on Louise Nevelson at the Museum of Modern Art, (See box 8, folder 12) (Box 10)
    - Colette Roberts, Lecture on Louise Nevelson, Notes and Excerpts from Interviews, (See box 9, items 25 and 30) (Box 10)
    - Colette Roberts, Radio Interview by Eden Gray, (See box 9, item 2) (Box 10)
    - Colette Roberts, Teaching French Language Classes, (See box 7, item 3 and box 10, item 19) (Box 10)
    - Miriam Schapiro, (See box 9, item 8) (Box 10)
    - Ethel Schwabacher, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 6)
    - Leon Polk Smith, 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 7)
    - Kenneth Snelson, 1968; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 8)
    - Pierre Soulages, circa 1965; (1 original sound tape reel, and 1 sound tape reel of excerpts) (Box 10, Item 9)
    - Raphael Soyer, (See box 9, item 27) (Box 10)
    - Hedda Sterne, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 10)
    - Hedda Sterne, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 11)
    - Richard Tuttle, 1970; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 12)
    - Frédérique Duran, 1970; (1 side of 1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 13)
    - Bernar Venet, 1969; (3 sound tape reels; see also box 8, item 24, in which Venet is interviewed with Ivan Karp) (Box 10, Item 14)
    - Marie Helena Vieira da Silva, 1966; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 15)
    - Marie Helena Vieira da Silva, 1967; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 16)
    - Ruth Vollmer, 1970; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 17)
    - Robert Watts, between 1961 and 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 18)
    - Colette Roberts, French Lesson on Marcel Duchamp, between 1961 and 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 19)
    - Jane Wilson, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 20)
    - Jack Youngerman, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 21)
    - Jack Youngerman, between 1961 and 1971; (3 sound tape reels) (Box 10, Item 22)
    - Adja Yunkers, 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 23)
    - Blank Tapes (Box 10)
      - Unrecorded reels labelled "François Baschet", 1971; (2 sound tape reels) (Box 10, Item 24)
      - Unrecorded reel labelled "Gabrielle Picabia", between 1961 and 1971; (1 sound tape reel) (Box 10, Item 25)